## MARK THOMAS CLAYTON

ntario, California 91761

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/markthomasclayton/

Digital Resume: https://claytonscreations.github.io/

(909)203-2299 **Q**clytn579@gmail.com

Experienced and organized Project Manager with skills in Excel, VBA, Python, JavaScript, HTML and SQL from my Certificate in Data Analytics & Visualizations. Enjoy leveraging my skill set to identify, analyze, and implement process improvement opportunities. Strengths include my self-motivated and analytical personality with the ability to collaborate across diverse groups and presentation skills make me a valuable addition to any team.

# **Key Skills**

Leadership | Problem Solving | Communication | Teamwork | Adaptability Self-motivation | Public Speaking | Decision Making | Responsibility

Software Proficiency - SAP, Winshuttle | eDMRM (OpenText) | ArcGIS, Survey123 | Adobe Pro, Photoshop Microsoft Office (including Excel (VBA), OneDrive, Outlook, PowerPoint, Project, Publisher, SharePoint, Visio & Word) Data Analytics & Visualizations - Tools: Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, & Tableau | Libraries/Databases: Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy, SciPy, Plotly, D3, Leaflet, Flask, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, & Bootstrap

# **Coding Projects**

# University of Irvine, Certificate in Data Analysis & Visualizations

September 2021 – March 2022

GitHub Profile: https://github.com/ClaytonsCreations

- Extract, Load, Transform (ELT) Project: Python, Pandas, Jupyter Notebook, JSON, csv, and PostgreSQL.
- **Tell a Story with Data Project:** Python, SQL, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, Leaflet, BeautifulSoup, and D3.

### Experience

# SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA EDISON 2005 – Present

**Advisor** - Asset Performance Engineering, Condition Monitoring & Analytics

May 2017 - Present

Project manage the entire <u>Generation Wildfire Mitigation Plan (WMP)</u> which includes asset inspections, remediations, vegetation management, and system hardening activities.

- Coordinated the completion of over 400 inspections across SCE Territory including training field crews and technicians and provided regular updates to senior leadership throughout the organization.
- Reviewed all inspection data and processed notifications to field crews to reduce and remediate possible ignition risks. Ensured remediation of all findings within compliance deadlines.
- Managed and supported Advisor's to ensure execution and compliance of the Expanded Clearance vegetation project and analysis of 9 hydro control circuits.
- Led the cross coordination between Generation and T&D to remove 3 unsafe Agnew transmission towers.
- **Project managed the grounding studies and lightning arrestor assessments of 33 sites** and coordinated mitigation action identified by vendor.
- Led low voltage site analysis that identified sites across the territory for ways to reduce ignition risk such as battery/solar conversions, covered conductor, or other ignition reduction opportunities.
- **Collaborated with WMP leads and departments** to develop project plans, goals, and milestones. Often respond to requests from regulatory agencies like the CPUC/WSD.

Manage the <u>Gen-T&D Roles and Responsibilities Alignment (RRA)</u> which includes coordinating meetings with the Union and key stakeholders on changes.

- Developed project plan to replace the Catalina Transformers to improve reliability of power and reduce point of failure.
- Oversaw the Generation Maintenance update process to incorporated existing technology that reduced costs associated with purchasing and integrating new systems.
- Compliance liaison between 3 OUs to streamline coordination and communications.

- Worked with the Generation Diversity and Inclusion action team to develop a hiring guide to assist Managers
  in taking steps necessary to attracting and hiring a diverse workforce.
- Completed my yellow belt certification courses and 2 kaizen continuous improvement events. I continue to stay certified by completing a minimum of 1 kaizen every 6 months.
- Managed SAP requests such as developing job aids, creating processes, maintenance plan creation, FLOC/Equip updates, data pulls and comparisons that require pivot tables, vlook-up and matching exercises.
- Assisted project manage the Penstock Inspections Program by acting as a field rep. for contractors, collecting
  engineering data, providing scheduling assistance, and reviewing timesheets and purchase order documents.
- Redesigned 15 Portal (SharePoint Intranet) pages reducing scrolling/clicking by an average of 50%.

#### **Program/Project Analyst 3 -** *Documents & Records Management*

November 2015 – May 2017

Information Steward for Generation Organization managing the annual review & dispositioning of records, planning & executing records clean-up events, and being the Point of Contact for questions.

- Pulled from regular duties to **lead the process and procedures activity** for the new Asset Management Program being developed to ensure proper development and storage of newly created documents.
- Worked closely with IT and our clients to identify, classify, and move documents from shared folders to
  eDMRM. Continued to be the administrator of those libraries to help clients when retrieving and storing
  business records as well as managing access.
- **Led a segment of a drawing project** which incorporated analyzing data to determine which records were outdated and subsequently worked with a vendor on validation and updates that decreased errors.

### **Construction Material Coordinator 1 -** *Corporate Drawing Management*

April 2010 – November 2015

Responsible for records management data related to the engineering documents library 'CRT Dashboard' and user interface 'CDM Library' which are used by multiple departments and vendors for construction projects.

- Processed engineering documents / drawings by completing a quality check of drawings, data entry of key elements, electronic scanning, and distribution of the engineering package.
- Key project team member during the design and implementation of new engineering documents library CRT Dashboard and user interface CDM Library.
- Updated the Business Continuity process for all emergency hard drives and decreased the time to update, developed a schedule to reduce time away from sites and developed better tracking forms.
- Managed confidential documents and materials such as Critical Energy Infrastructure Information (CEII) and North American Reliability Corporation, Critical Infrastructure Protection (NERC CIP).

Began career at SCE as a Student Utility Worker (2005 – 2006) and Customer Service Representative (2006 – 2010)

### Education

Certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization, UC Irvine	March 2022
The Leverage Effect Certificate, UC Irvine, Paul Merage School of Business	December 2020
Yellow Belt Certification, Southern California Edison Internal Training Program	September 2019
The Dynamic Leader Certificate, UC San Diego, Rady School of Management	November 2018
Project Management Certificate, University of Phoenix	March 2016
AutoCAD Essentials Certificate, Autodesk	February 2016
The Innovative Leader Certificate, UC San Diego, Rady School of Management	June 2015
The Strategic Leader Certificate, UC San Diego, Rady School of Management	May 2014